Whitman County Historic Resources Survey 1986-1987
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Whitman County Historic Resources Survey
1986-1987
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 555
Washington State Office of Archaeology and Historic Preservation
3 containers. 1 linear feet of shelf space.
Reports and a directory of historic properties throughout Whitman County, Washington. Project Director, Mary Reed.
The Washington State Office of Archaeology and Historic Preservation maintains a register of historic sites and buildings, and archaeological sites, for use by land planning offices, cultural agencies, and the general public. Information is assembled by a variety of means. In Whitman County the basic survey of historic sites was prepared by a contract research teams of four individuals, headed by Mary Reed of Pullman.
The materials are arranged in the order given by the research team. The basic form is an area-by-area grouping of properties.
This collection is open for research use.
Photocopies of the reports of the Whitman County Historic Resource Survey were placed with the Washington State University Libraries in 1987 (Accession MS87-01) by the State Office of Archaeology and Historic Preservation.
Further copies of this material were depositied with the Whitman County Library and the Whitman County Historical Society.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington (State). Office of Archaeology and Historic Preservation --Archives
Reed, Mary E. --Archives
Historic buildings--Washington (State)--Whitman County--Directories
Pacific Northwest History; Architecture; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Whitman County Historic Resource Survey, Sept. 1986 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- Agriculture Study Unit, Sept. 27, 1985 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
- Township 11N: 38-1 to 38-4 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
- Township 12N: 38-5 to 38-18 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
- Township 13N: 38-19 to 38-31 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
- Township 13N: 38-32 to 38-48 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
- Township 13N: 38-49 to 38-60 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
- Township 14N: 38-61 to 38-76 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
- Township 14N: 38-77 to 38-92 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
- Township 14N: 38-93 to 38-102 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
- Township 15N: 38-110 to 38-131 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
- Township 15N: 38-132 to 38-154 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
- Township 16N: 38-155 to 38-178 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
- Township 16N: 38-179 to 38-202 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
- Township 17N: 38-203 to 38-221 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
- Township 17N: 38-222 to 38-240 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
- Township 17N: 38-241 to 38-258 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
- Township 18N: 38-259 to 38-277 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
- Township 19N: 38-278 to 38-296 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
- Township 19N: 38-297 to 38-315 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
- Township 20N: 38-316 to 38-335 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
- Township 22N: 38-336 to 38-351 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
- Albion 15N: 38-352 to 38-358 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-359 to 38-375 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-376 to 38-393 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-394 to 38-419 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-420 to 38-445 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-446 to 38-472 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
- Colfax Historic District 16N: 38-473 to 38-498 (Box-folder 1 / 29)
- Colton 13N: 38-499 to 38-519 (Box-folder 1 / 30)
- Diamond 16N/17N: 38-520 to 38-532 (Box-folder 2 / 31)
- Dusty 15N: 38-533 to 38-535 (Box-folder 2 / 32)
- Elberton 17N: 38-536 to 38-559 (Box-folder 2 / 33)
- Elberton 17N: 38-560 to 38-582 (Box-folder 2 / 34)
- Endicott 17N: 38-583 to 38-610 (Box-folder 2 / 35)
- Endicott 17N: 38-611 to 38-639 (Box-folder 2 / 36)
- Ewan 19N: 38-640 to 38-646 (Box-folder 2 / 37)
- Farmington 18N: 38-647 to 38-676 (Box-folder 2 / 38)
- Garfield 18N: 38-677 to 38-697 (Box-folder 2 / 39)
- Garfield 18N: 38-698 to 38-719 (Box-folder 2 / 40)
- Hay 14N: 38-720 to 38-728 (Box-folder 2 / 41)
- Hooper 15N: 38-729 to 38-737 (Box-folder 2 / 42)
- Johnson 13N/14N: 38-738 to 38-740 (Box-folder 2 / 43)
- LaCrosse 15N: 38-741 to 38-764 (Box-folder 2 / 44)
- Lamont 20N: 38-765 to 38-776 (Box-folder 2 / 45)
- Madison 20N: 38-778 to 38-793 (Box-folder 2 / 46)
- Oakesdale 19N: 38-794 to 38-814 (Box-folder 2 / 47)
- Oakesdale 19N: 38-815 to 38-834 (Box-folder 2 / 48)
- Palouse 16N: 38-835 to 38-857 (Box-folder 2 / 49)
- Palouse 16N: 38-858 to 38-888 (Box-folder 2 / 50)
- Palouse 16N: 38-889 to 38-916 (Box-folder 2 / 51)
- Pine City 20N: 38-917 to 38-925 (Box-folder 2 / 52)
- Pullman 14N: 38-926 to 38-944 (Box-folder 2 / 53)
- Pullman (College Hill) 15N: 38-945 to 38-977 (Box-folder 2 / 54)
- Pullman (College Hill) 14N: 38-978 to 38-1009 (Box-folder 2 / 55)
- Pullman (College Hill) 15N: 38-1010 to 38-1041 (Box-folder 2 / 56)
- Pullman (College Hill) 15N: 38-1042 to 38-1074 (Box-folder 2 / 57)
- Pullman (Military Hill) 14N/15N: 38-1075 to 38-1091 (Box-folder 2 / 58)
- Pullman (Pioneer Hill) 14N: 38-1092 to 38-1110 (Box-folder 2 / 59)
- Pullman (Pioneer Hill) 14N: 38-1111 to 38-1129 (Box-folder 2 / 60)
- Pullman (Sunnyside Hill) 14N: 38-1130 to 38-1141 (Box-folder 2 / 61)
- Pullman (WSU Campus) 14N: 38-1142 to 38-1175 (Box-folder 3 / 62)
- Rosalia 20N: 38-1176 to 38-1206 (Box-folder 3 / 63)
- St. John 18N/19N: 38-1207 to 38-1236 (Box-folder 3 / 64)
- Steptoe 18N: 38-1237 to 38-1248 (Box-folder 3 / 65)
- Tekoa 20N: 38-1249 to 38-1271 (Box-folder 3 / 66)
- Tekoa 20N: 38-1272 to 38-1295 (Box-folder 3 / 67)
- Thornton 19N: 38-1311 to 38-1330 (Box-folder 3 / 68)
- Uniontown 12N: 38-1331 to 38-1351 (Box-folder 3 / 69)
- Winona 17N: 38-1352 to 38-1361 (Box-folder 3 / 70)